Dominic Jones

Senior Full-Stack Engineer

With over nine years of experience, I have delivered high-impact projects for government orgs, start-ups, SMEs, and big tech (Google). I am experienced in backend and frontend development as well as cloud technologies to build scalable, event-driven microservices.

dominic23jones@gmail.com

00447400097087



Remote - Cardiff, UK



github.com/haakym

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Developer Mac International

06/2022 - 11/2022

Academic admissions

Remote, UK

- Transformed business from a manual operation, WhatsApp and Excel, to a Laravel-powered web app automating communications and operations.
- Streamline business processes with partner company by centralising customer data via a custom built HubSpot integration.
- Empower users with student referral tracking and analytics dashboard.

Web Development Training Specialist

Advanced Systems Group (Google External Workforce)

03/2022 - 05/2022

Remote, UK

Vendor at Google's Learner Experience Lab

- Created training material for Google using my web development expertise and technical writing skills for a front-end web developer curriculum.
- Improved user experience by identifying reliability issues with CodeLabs.
- Improved team collaboration by creating guidelines on common issues raised in content review process streamline the content review process.

PHP Developer Elucidat

03/2019 - 03/2022

Remote, UK

Elearning authoring tool and platform for global business

- Awarded employee of the month for the creation of several microservices within a quarter to deliver a new product while establishing the groundwork for future microservice development using Lumen.
- Successfully managed releases to production, combining contributions across several teams and resolving issues with the QA team resulting in a smooth release process.
- Supported timely completion of new features from the product roadmap and maintenance of the core product as a member of an agile product team involved in planning, development, testing and release stages.
- Assisted my colleagues personal development by mentoring junior team members through code-reviews and pair programming.
- Championed a code-review template across all GitHub repos to improve developer experience by maintaining standards and security resulting in improved code quality while reducing the time of the code-review process.
- Automated the app translation process by creating a command line tool using the Symfony Console component to import and export translation files saving the company time and money.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PHP Laravel **PHPUnit** MySQL AWS: DynamoDB, SQS, S3, AMQ Node.js **Javascript** Vue.is React.js HTML **CSS** Redis Gherkin/Selenium Docker **Open API Specifications REST APIs** Microservices

PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT

Apache

AWS Academy (12/2022 - Present)

Course to gain certification in AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner and Solutions Architect associate and professional certificates.

Technical Writing

SSO: SAML, LDAP

SOLID

Improved my technical writing skills by completing Google's technical writing courses for engineers.

StackOverflow

I enjoy helping others overcome coding challenges as well as my own and have been a regular contributor to the StackOverflow community with 10k+ reputation - stackoverflow.com/u/648247.

Mentor at Code Your Future

Code Your Future is a non-profit organisation supporting refugees with the dream of becoming developers. As a mentor, I led a class teaching JavaScript and tutored students 1-to-1 remotely.

Online Courses

I develop my skills through online courses such as laracasts.com, testdrivenlaravel.com, freecodecamp.com, courses by Wes Bos such as learnnode.com and reactforbeginners.com.

Podcasts

I keep abreast of the latest tech developments via podcasts including Syntax, Full Stack Radio, The Laravel News Podcast, Software Engineering Daily, Code Newbies, Indie Hackers.

Open Source

I participate in the OS community through Github with contributions to various projects such as the Laravel framework and participate in OS events like Hacktoberfest.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Developer Openplay

10/2018 - 03/2019

London, UK

Sport and leisure software

- Swiftly familiarized myself with a large codebase enabling a smooth transition towards a new system while maintaining the functionality of the legacy system.
- Demonstrated the ability to learn new technologies effectively, including Electron and web-sockets, to support the development of a web-based NFC card reader feature. This expanded the product offering by integrating membership card functionality.

Web Developer

Saudi Arabian Cultural Bureau

10/2013 - 09/2018

London, UK

Bridge between educational and research institutions in UK and KSA

- Improved staff efficiency and customer experience by replacing a PDF report form with a web-based academic reports system enabling UK universities to provide student progress updates to scholarship sponsors.
- Modernised the HR department's operations by moving a paper-based holiday and sick leave process to a bespoke web based system that utilised LDAP and Active Directory to access staff details and enable Single Sign On.
- Improved staff efficiency and customer happiness by drastically reducing a
 months long waiting period for document attestation to a period of days by
 implementing a web-based attestation system with improved user
 experience and automation of several processes such as a web based PDF
 stamper for staff use.
- Contributed to the success of a career-fair and graduation ceremony for thousands of attendees by implementing a web-based event registration and check-in system that streamlined the event check-in process.
- Successfully delivered a multitude of web-based systems while working as the sole developer responsible for all stages of application development.

Learning Technologist

College of North West London

03/2013 - 09/2013

London, UK

- Awarded department award at 2013 Staff Awards for excellent service and advocacy of ELearning technologies.
- Helped students find funding by implementing a bespoke web-based financial eligibility checker.
- Supported staff with one-on-one training and workshops to gain skills in using ELearning technologies.
- Administered and maintained college intranet using PHP-based VLE Moodle.

EDUCATION

- Computer Science, MSc
 Oxford Brookes University
- Computer Science, BSc Queen Mary UoL

INTERESTS

Arabic

Basketball

Coffee brewing

Home cooking and baking

Open Source